Ryan Workman

Summary

I am a full-stack web developer with experience in Ruby, Rails, SQL database management, React, Redux, and other JavaScript libraries. I am currently working as a front-end engineer for Dish Network where I have spent time on multiple teams using Angular and React to implement solutions for internal sales agents and external clients. I am currently working on Dish's Sling TV application, developing new features including the critically-acclaimed 'NBA League Pass' and 'NBA Team Pass.'

Projects

BuchaBuddy (Web Application) - http://www.buchabuddy.com

An inventory tracking application for kombucha homebrewers

- After getting into homebrewing kombucha, I wanted the ability to track all of my ingredients, recipes, capital, etc. BuchaBuddy is an open-source web application that helps homebrewers like me make the best kombucha.
- Tech stack: Ruby, Rails, Angular, Redux, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, Capistrano GitHub: https://github.com/buchabuddy/buchabuddy

Passr (Ruby Gem) - https://rubygems.org/gems/passr

A simple gem handling password generation, encryption and decryption.

- I created this open-source, lightweight gem to create randomly generated passwords handling encryption and decryption using RbNaCl::Libsodium.
- Tech stack: Ruby, Bundler, RbNaCl::Libsodium.

GitHub: https://github.com/rdavid1099/passr

Employment

Sling TV/ Dish Network - Full-Stack Web Developer May 2017 to Current Denver, CO.

- Add and maintain functionality of Dish's Sling Television Web Application using React, Angular and Docker
- Create tools for direct and indirect sales agents using AngularJS on multiple instances of the Jive Software platform

Trelora - Full-Stack Web Developer

Dec 2016 to Feb 2017

Denver, CO.

- Internship and contract work developing new features using React for internal file-storage API and signage app
- Work closely with CTO Keith Hunniford and his team to solve complex problems and enhance site's U/X

KDVR Fox31 Denver - News Producer

Jul 2014 to Jun 2016

Denver, CO.

KPTV Fox 12 Oregon - News Producer

Aug 2012 to May 2014

Portland, OR.

KALB News Channel 5 - News Producer

Sep 2011 to Jul 2012

Alexandria, LA.

Contact

(303) 815-0866 rdavid1099@gmail.com LinkedIn.com/in/Ryan-Workman GitHub.com/RDavid1099 Medium.com/@rdavid1099

Education

Turing School of Software & Design Certificate for Web Development, Ruby/Rails/JS - 2017 University of Northern Colorado B.A. Journalism - 2011

Skills

Web Development

Front-End

- HTML/ CSS
- JavaScript/ TypeScript
- Angular
- React
- Redux

Back-End

- Ruby/ Rails
- ActiveRecord
- Redis
- SQL

Server Management

- Bash/ Shell Script
- DigitalOcean Droplet
- Capistrano